NVIDIA has agreed
to acquire Hugging Face
for $12.9 billion.
This gives NVIDIA
control of one
of the most important
distribution
and collaboration
platforms in AI.
Just to run
through some numbers,
Hugging Face hosts
more than 3 million
AI models, 18 million
users, 200K companies,
500K datasets,
and more than 1 million
applications.
The CEO did say
that Hugging Face
will continue to operate
as an open platform
and developers will not
be required to use
NVIDIA hardware.
This is definitely
a huge win for NVIDIA
because they already
dominate
the accelerators
that are used to train
and run many
of the industry's
largest models.
So owning Hugging Face
will give NVIDIA
a direct connection
to the huge developer
community, no matter
which model will win.
Also around 2023,
their valuation
was around $4.5 billion
and now we're like 3X
that valuation.